<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on QuaRCS lab</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on QuaRCS lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/portfolio/all-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/all-publications/</guid>
      <description>Research publications  Further information including current projects, slides, and summaries are available here: https://quarcs-lab.org/research
 Mendez, Carlos. 2020. Convergence Clubs in Labor Productivity and its Proximate Sources: Evidence from Developed and Developing Countries. Springer. [E-book version] [Printed version]
Aginta, Harry. 2020. &amp;ldquo;Spatial dynamics of consumer price in Indonesia: Convergence clubs and conditioning factors.&amp;rdquo; Asia-Pacific Journal of Regional Science, Forthcoming. [Published version]
Aginta, Harry. 2020. &amp;ldquo;Does the law of one price hold in 82 Indonesian cities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research projects</title>
      <link>/portfolio/research-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/research-projects/</guid>
      <description>Main research lines  A more detailed description of current projects, slides, and summaries are available at https://quarcs-lab.org/research
   (A) The wealth of subnations: A view from outer space
  (B) Subnational inequality in human development in Latin America
  (C) Regional development, growth, and inequality in Indonesia
  (D) Regional inequality and convergence in Thailand
  (E) Spatiotemporal methods for regional inequality
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book launch</title>
      <link>/portfolio/book-mendez2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/book-mendez2020/</guid>
      <description>About the book  Testing for economic convergence across countries has been a central issue in the literature of economic growth and development. This book introduces a modern framework to study the cross-country convergence dynamics of labor productivity and its proximate sources: capital accumulation and aggregate efficiency. In particular, recent convergence dynamics of developed as well as developing countries are evaluated through the lens of a non-linear dynamic factor model and a clustering algorithm for panel data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets and tutorials</title>
      <link>/portfolio/data-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/data-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Datasets:   Gunawan, A. and Mendez, C. (2020). Provincial income, convergence clubs and structural change in Indonesia 2001-2017: An interactive and automated exploration in R. R Studio/RPubs. Available at https://rpubs.com/quarcs-lab/data-indonesia-34-provinces-clubs-2001-2017
  Mendez, C., Siew, S., Chan, R., and Tang, D. (2020). Productivity differences in the ASEAN community: An interactive and automated exploration in R. R Studio/RPubs. Available at https://rpubs.com/quarcs-lab/data-productivity-asean-1972-2017
  Mendez, C. (2020). Regional inequality across countries 1992-2012: An interactive and automated exploration in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QuaRCS-lab webinar series</title>
      <link>/portfolio/webinars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/webinars/</guid>
      <description>QuaRCS-lab webinar series  The QuaRCS-lab webinar series provides a platform for researchers around the world to present and discuss their latest quantitative research about sustainable development, economic growth, and regional inequality. If you are interested in these topics as well as quantitative methods, please register and join our mailing list.
   The webinars take place once or twice in a month via ZOOM. The time and date can vary depending on the location of the speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning community</title>
      <link>/portfolio/learning-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/learning-community/</guid>
      <description>Learning community  Our private learning community provides a platform for learning the research methods and tools that are used across the research lines of the QuaRCS lab.
 Apply for access here: https://www.facebook.com/groups/QuaRCS.Lab</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
